Translation/Subtitle: jls001999 (jls001999@gmail.com)
Review/Proofreading: coralsundy (coralsundy@gmail.com)
(Paid by coralsundy for the translation, personal use only)
Ani Imoto / Older Brother, Younger Sister (1976)
You idiot!
Shut up, you bastard!
Damn…
Oh, that’s a great voice.
Ino-san, someone is waiting for you, you know
How about a special room at the hotel Isaberry?
Rolling bed is good?
I thought you went there.
I really am an alien.
I thought it was just a little too different,
but not in that sense
I, uh, have a single Toyo antenna from the era of extendable antennas
In the morning, something...
It sucks...
Okay, start! Now, who will win the $1,000,000?
Thank you so much.
Mom?
Hey—are you coming back?
Want to have oden?
I don't want to eat that.
I've heard Ray-chan is back.
Yeah—who said that?
Ray-chan's off today,so she came, right?
She quit her job.
Why? Did something happen at the factory?
She's there for six years.
She's a veteran.
When I walked past Marutoya,
The old lady said something weird.
Tokiko Obasan said what?
She told me not to become like my older sister by fooling around with men.
What’s all this about being teased by a guy?
Is that a lie?
Drink it
Now, we started selling lemonades too, you know?
The old, nostalgic Ginza lemonade...
Hey come on.
Eating tokoroten is delicious, too.
Try a sample
You must be hungry, right?
Eat a lot.
It’s okay
It’s okay already, Mom.
Mon-chan is not teasing the men
Don't make a fool of her.
She looks in her eyes just like her sister’s
Don’t go out with that woman ’s sister
She sent a lot of money for living expenses, so I thought it was strange.
Apparently, she tricked a man and took his money.
If you and your shameful little sister pull the same stunt all over again, it’s going to be a big deal, you hear me?
If it’s that old woman Tokiko, for someone like a married-to-the-house daughter, she’s been using the men over there
She says that ever since these days her blood-rushing craving has become like this—chronic stress from all this yakimochi stuff—so
I'm frustrated.
Huh?
I’m the one on duty at the shop
Old lady
Oh, please come in
We would like to rent a boat.
Please go to another store.
There are no boats available for rent right now.
Can we bring that out?
That boat is broken.
Do you mean everyone is piling up water?
It’s dangerous if it sinks that
Damn it.
What does my older brother do?
Even on his day off, he didn’t come?
I don't want him coming to help, because he ends up breaking the boat.
Boat?
No, it's sales revenue.
It all disappears all of a sudden
Dad, keep quiet?
Dad takes the sales revenue and runs off with them.
So Inokichi just put our sales, and then he ends up taking it away
Both of them are just so
awful—nothing will work out, right?
So that's what it is
Why do you let them do such things?
He says he is here for a part-time job.
It is strange for him to come to my house for a part-time job.
This isn’t helping out, is it?
Yeah.
Yeah?
It’s no use now
He's just careless anyway.
Hey, I’ll give it to you, Mom.
This.
I don't need.
Why?
I plan to work somewhere other than the factory in the future.
Right now, I’m studying with a correspondence
course to get a bookkeeping/accounting qualification
That way, I could even become an accountant for a bigger
company or the secretary of a tax consulting office.
Then I'll take it.
Thank you very much.
Here you go.
It’s only you, so you won’t have to suffer too much
Ino-san.
Wait.
It is still daytime.
I will walk with you as far as over there to see you off.
It is still daytime but...
Damn it.
Who?
This seat is available.
I made it.
Hey, look, look!
Hey Ino.
You...
Play it in there with yourself!
What are you doing? You’re not supposed to be doing it right here
You don't need to hit me.
Go home—you’re off today,right?
I don’t want to see the face of some bastard. .
Besides, when I see you and my mom looking so drained, it makes my hate flare up, Get out of here!
Are you okay? he has to be kind to elderly people
who are you?
I’m Lumi from Snack Paradise
Come in once and I’ll serve you
Hey,bring him next time.
You idiot!
Go home!
Oh, don’t make such a scary face
Stop it. she has nothing to do with this!
What?
I can't stand it anymore, you bastard!
I won’t take losing!
Stop it!
Go home!
I will teach you discipline.
What's wrong?
Damn it.
I’m being beaten,His power is weak.
I used to feel dizzy,
The time he hit me before, he used a lot of force.
but now he's just getting worse
Why are you sleeping?
You’re probably dreaming again with a guy.
It’s disgusting.
then stop blabbering that stumbling, stupid TV program.
You shoved some bastard—who knows where
And in the end you even went so far as to toss it right out through my belly button!
It hurts, It hurts —you just lays out complaints
You really don't do anything.
You are always sleeping at home.
So you want to turn someone else into a good-for-nothing?
I don't want you to get pregnant and hear a baby crying.
Your man is smarter than you, so he will leave you if there is no need for you.
What's the hell?
You shielded a man who wouldn't even give his name.
Do you still love him?
You are stupid.
You are truly a fool.
Take the kids and go straight
to the middle of Tokyo
You should just perish right there.
An idiot like you needs that.
Hey,hey.
While you’re standing around doing this,
even an hour—or even a whole day—becomes impossible to undo
What are we going to do?
Other than that, resolve the issue before it's too late.
Will you listen to what I say?
You are truly stubborn.
You are stupid.
Come with me.
I’m not saying anything bad!
Please don't bully me anymore.
I take care of things myself.
I’m not going to owe anyone anything
None of your business
I take care of things myself.
What are you going to do?
I am already thinking it
I think about it every day,
but I’ll figure something out—somehow
Do what?
That's all I can think about.
Just keep it quiet
Oh I see.
so you mean you’ll take care of your own mess yourself
Then go ahead and show it off properly
Don't fool of me.
I was born in the river and raised there
I see I see.
This is year ten.
The prefectural government paved that area with concrete.
It’s because it’s any-any prefecture, you know
Back then, it was all thanks to the abilities of the goddess
from the woman’s side of Mr. Yokono Akazawa, you know
Thanks to her, there was absolutely no stinginess with words in the past.
Oh, that’s right
Because you don’t know anything at all
Those people these days are just unfortunate
It was a good time, after all
The river was also flowing normally at the time.
That is because a floodgate was built.
That’s common sense, right?
That is only natural.
I was trying to tell you a story about the good old days.
If they doesn’t know, that means they’re strong, huh?
Japan is already bad.
Japan today is controlled by people who lack manners.
I wouldn’t feel like it’s worth.
Boss.
on New Year’s, a group of pregnant women,
all of them come together and, in your yard, got new years's gift.
Those days were quite lavish
You were always the leader at the festival.
And when it comes to that, everything worked out like that, yeah…
Doing things like that
I hate doing things like that.
Yeah! If that's the case—
just as I’d expect
I'm so happy and moved
Boss
I grew up near river
and by I was fifteen, I became an Adult
Till I’m fully on my own at twenty
We—raised with our feet left covered in blood, among fresh green leaves, bamboo, and dark sasa
Even if the torrential flooding during the
rainy season kept happening every day—
whether it was during the sudden outflow
when the snow melt was flowing fast—
You did a perfect job.
it held firm down in the riverbed, all the way to the bottom of the River
What a remarkable skill
Of course, boss—you're great.
Me and the river, we lived together and die
That’s what I believe.
Well, thanks again for the wonderful hospitality.
Well, since my older sister came back home for something like that,
She's saying I’m not allowed to talk to her—
I mean, they think their whole life is just leaving money behind
Why would you go and become an adopted child in a place like that?
No matter what—if your parents decided when you were born,
you can still just go back, can't you?
Even if things between relatives turned sour...
I mean, my his real father has asthma
royal—so there are deliveries left to make, you know
You can’t keep going to a place like this.
come to Tokyo sooner
Then we’ll be able to date whenever we want without feeling like we have to hold back
Yeah, you trained at a big supermarket
Before long, you’ll be the store manager, and on her days off you’ll be standing there with a girl, arms crossed
You are a idiot—there’s no fight
If I even got that store, I’d just end up struggling
with inheritance tax
Yeah, that’s how it goes
There’s no point trying hard in a place like this
Every time I come, That river looks like a puddle.
Just humans, all of them, like garbage
They drive up in their cars and come
I'm home!
What are you doing?
Are you going somewhere?
Hey
San-chan's here
I have to get the meal ready soon
I found some really good sashimi
And, you know,I'll fry up a piece of katsu, too
Let's eat together
If I cook sardines with pickled plums and eat them, it’ll be quite smooth on the
After packing your bags, where are you going?
You're too noisy.
Leave her alone
She can’t even take care of what she need to handle
Don't say like that.
Even if you say that, a mother’s a mother, you know
I told you from the start that something like this would never end well
You threw her out of the house
Not all factory workers are like that.
That's why you're a doting parent.
Thinking that only your own daughter is smart...
Since you swagger around
this is what happens
It’s because Mom’s kind of sloppy,
She come back and
messing things up like this, you know—
I’m back.
I just made sure the place was shut up pretty tight, okay?
Oh, should I help?
You said you’ll take a bath first.
Sister takes the bath too,right?
She can't take the bath.
She have to clean the room.
Where are you going, huh?
Sis.
Ino
you said too much.
You have no right to speak ill of others.
What's the hell?
You gave birth to a foolish daughter.
You’re the one who keeps being moody and either going to work or not going
Whenever you visit your parents, all you do is complain.
There are times when it's okay to get angry, and times when it's not
You should let your dad get angry
You don't get to butt in like you're so great
Even your dad is going to stop talking and just keep quiet now, so
Don’t you think we all should just be quiet and keep things calm from now on?
I'll cook soon so take a bath first.
Where's my shoes?
I'll wash your back?
I left them here
Why don’t we get in together?
Before long there’ll be food ready,
Sis.
so stop bothering me.
What’s with you acting so arrogant and sulking?
You’re the one who’s behaving all high and mighty
They send me gifts on Mother's Day.
but all you do is come here to get money.
Whenever you show up, it’s nothing but trouble
Bros
it’s been a long time since she came back, and you shouldn’t be saying things like that to your sister.
What?
Just get out.
If I’m here, I'm causing trouble for everyone
Oh, yeah—that’s for your sake,
Your sister couldn’t manage a proper marriage into a good home anymore
Bro, My sis have been working in the factory
for six years just to get me to school
I can’t help thinking, how am I supposed to repay her for that?
I want to get my certification quickly so I can let my older sister take it easy.
San-chan....
I was planning to go out once the sun went down
Sis...
so what are you planning to do about it?
I'll ask my friend who works at the hospital
It’s not like it’s already too late
There are other methods as well.
Brother
You know, right after you got out of junior high,
didn’t you lure a girl into the back area and get caught by Dad?
Back then, I was the one who protected you, you know
Tell him she’s a girl from your classmate.
And then, brother—
You were thanking (me) by doing the hand-over-hand gesture in a dark place, weren’t you?
It's just that...
Why do you treat me like that?
I am very sad that you said that to me.
I will try asking someone else.
It's not good.
The name "Mon" means "the gate of excruciating agony."
It’s named because you pass out when you leave—the name says so
My sister’s name San is the name of the terrible—like, it’s basically the one from the worst
"Ino," part of my name, means "pig."
Our father is the kind of fool who would give us a name like this.
I can’t just keep quiet
You say, 'Settle this quickly,'
What do you mean?
I will raise my own child myself.
This feeling—it's something you just can't understand
You are a truly terrible person.
I am not going to worry you anymore
Alright then,
Sis...
Just wait
Mon
Sis.
Ino.
Watch on the bath.
Fire is dangerous.
Sis.
Sis! Wait!
Sis!
Sis! Come back home!
You should go back home.
Mon.
Hold on.
Mother! Are you alright?
Hey.
Please take this.
Thank you for coming all the way.
I just came to say hello.
You bastard!
You damn fool!
Don't make a fool of us.
Don't be too violent with her.
Because she’s Rosa’s maid, I’m letting it
slide and giving her a bit of extra leeway
She asked us to pay for the cream,
so I got mad
I am really frustrated.
It can't be helped.
Remember.
You get it?
You bastard!
Just calm down already!
Everyone says, 'This is a temple of art,
Your presence is an eyesore.
I told her, though
She shouldn't take money by force the people at the cabaret
But, like,She came yesterday, too.
Just a little bit of money
Who do we owe that to?
Sorry to trouble you
I’ll make sure to tell her.
so—go call Mon-chan
I’ll get her to apologize properly
Have a seat, boss.
But I am not really a boss yet
Come on.
Excuse me.
I’m sorry.
Even if she know a man like that—
She can’t expect it to be an appeal for the stage, right?
Well, I guess she’s a junior from the factory
Everyone is cold to her.
In the end, she came to rely on me, so…
She probably don’t plan to become a nude dancer, though
If it pays well,
She might change her mind again
Oh she's here
Come in.
Mom-chan
Are you planning to take the stage
She can’t
It's impossible.
That would be… not now
Oh, I see
I know someone in Hanamaki
Leave her over there
At hot-spring resort?
Where?
It’s Tohoku
Just go there to recuperate, and once you’ve figured things out,
you can have it handled by paying back your obligations
You should become a dancer., you know
Until I give a birth
I’ll put up with anything
Please let me stay by your side.
Yeah
You are also very much into going to places you don't know.
She was very cute when she worked at the factory.
We’ve been encouraging each other through the tough times
She quit the factory because she was head over heels for him.
Why are you saying that now?
I ended up putting the company and the trumpet-maker Takeru on the back burner,
so it’s a loss, really
Even if you say that…
His asthma was unexpected.
Why are you acting like you don’t even know the inside story, too?
I am not the boss.
Well, think about it, Mon-chan
He tries to help you.
You'll only be in the way if you stay here.
Yeah.
This person? she's not here
Do you happen to have any idea?
Why don’t you apply to be a missing-person caller on TV?
See you again!
Thanks.
You came back late.
Couldn't you find her?
I hope you’ll know
Cheer up!
You’ve got to sleep—you’re up early tomorrow morning
In a year
Next is Yazaki, Yazaki.
Please press the buzzer if you are getting off.
Thank you very much
Thank you in advance.
We appreciate your cooperation
Likewise—thank you very much.
I look forward to working with you
Thanks so much for taking the time despite how busy you are—thank you
Hello?
You look like a completely different person.
How are sales of amazake?
No—it's the age of canned juice
Well, even though it was this busy schedule...
Just look—No one rents our boat.
Please try this amazake.
Did you hear anything from my older sister?
No?
Excuse me.
Welcome.
I heard about this from Akaza-san below.
Akaza’s shop is right here, but…
Well, I am Obata
Is Monko here?
What do you need?
She is in Tokyo right now
but actually, I want to talk about Monko
So I came, but...
Well, I’m sorry, but could you go over to our side?
Take him along and I'll go call your father
Come with me.
Yeah, Ken-chan, Ken-chan—could you do me a favor?
Please look after the shop.
I’ll give you some extra money later,
just for a little while—okay?
Sure.
Thank you very much.
Please wait a moment.
Father
Hurry up
Mon's guy.....
That person, a student, has arrived
Mon's?
Boss, I’ll bring the rope nets.
Sorry.
Please don’t do anything rough, okay?
Because the other person is young student
I guess he probably came to take care of regarding the baby
Dad, please—I’m begging you, don’t be rough, okay?
Does he have a bad appearance?
He looks like a very good student.
Please come in
Stay at the shop.
You can’t talk over there
Please feel free to come in.
So, please come here
Excuse me.
Let's have you state the request quickly.
I haven’t even greeted you yet
I am Obata
It is not as if I have been ignoring the problem until now.
I was being watched by the country's father so I didn’t have any chance to slip away
I’m really sorry.
I ended up causing such an inconvenience.
Actually, I’m going to Tokyo next time—
I’d like to cover various costs and, as a way of making up for it, to repay my parents in my own way
So,
I want to have an abortion for the sake of us both....
It may be presumptuous, but I tried to be as mindful of that point as I could
But then— you know?
Did she have a successful abortion?
Did you come because you wanted to feel at ease yourself?
No, I mean—
You just thought you could get things
sorted out for yourself and came here,or what?
Don't get me wrong.
I just want to make amends.
And you think we can make up for it
by paying the cost of taking care of the abortion?
No—if it’s at all something I can do...
Um… with all my sincerity.
She miscarried the baby
She has been out of her mind ever since.
So she is...
Mon
Where is she now?
If you don’t mind, could you tell me her address?
I want to meet her once and apologize
I need to clear things up emotionally—otherwise,
it’s just not going to work out, you know
Well...
I got her back for the moment,
but She left without saying where she was going.
Old lady
So, the store’s manju—
Older sister wants to give this to you.
San chan?
she said you should let the customers have it to eat
Ha ha, thanks for your hard work
Please have this steamed bun if you'd like.
Please.
She doesn't want to talk to you.
You should go home.
Mr. Obata, you'd better stop making crimes like this
This time, you were the one who won
He’s always the kind of person who is like that, you see
He’s not very good with words.
I'd like to have you come up for dinner,
but then, Mom, I’m afraid I've really inconvenienced you
Then, if—as it happens—Mon returns home…
I’ll say that you came to visit.
But once you find out her address, please ask about it
This is something small.
What's this?
Well, it’s a little embarrassing, but…
You don't need to do that.
Please take it.
I was hoping you wouldn’t have to worry like that
I thought I could have bought something as a souvenir, but
Please accept this at least.
If you don’t…
I probably won’t be of any help, but please, at least
take my feelings into consideration—please accept this
Please don’t just reject it and send it back
Please
Well then, I’ll take my leave with that
Please take care , and let your husband know
that I hope he won’t take it the wrong way
Excuse me.
So this is Ayame?
Yes
And what about this one?
Summer Chrysanthemums.
In summer, this must be beautiful, doesn’t it?
What color is the Summer Chrysanthemums?
It's a yellow flower
How old are you?
Me?
I just turned twenty-four
Oh, then just one year apart from Mon
Yes
This is my address, but—
Could you please give this to Mon?
Yes, I’m sure I will
Apparently, she also changes their mood from time to time
She sometimes comes over without even letting me know.
If you happen to meet her....
well—I'll tell her
Here—please have some
Well then, goodbye.
See you.
Hey, wait a minute!
I'm Mon's brother.
I have something to tell you.
Go down that far.
Did you meet Mon afterward?
Yes, I didn't
No?
You teased my younger sister and destroyed our family.
I can't believe you came to our house.
I have cherished her ever since she was a child.
I took her to the bathroom in the middle of the night.
I took care of her every day until she turned 17.
I never had a day where I didn’t see Mon, and I never had a day where I didn’t eat with her.
I have even told her where her mole is.
That’s why I couldn’t forgive her when you got her pregnant.
I tormented Mon—and in the end I treated her like a stray cat or a discarded dog, dirty and discarded.
Everyone hates me.
Everyone took her side.
I thought it was fine.
If I didn't do that, everyone would dislike Mon.
I thought she would lose the will to live.
You’re a student,
You were born a man—so if you just do what you’re meant to do,
You shouldn't have any more business with her.
Hah, it’s something that happens all the time, you know…
If you just throw it away, that’s the end of it
It won't be that easy、That's expecting too much、No such luck
I can’t just give you back cleanly—like that
Did you just come to apologize?
Rather than apologizing, I figured
Do you intend to leave her like that?
If anything comes up, we’ll consult with each other as the two of us
Consult?
You mean you’re going to get married?
If things go that way... maybe
Don't you lie!
Don't be violent towards me.
What?
I know you don't care about anything.
Just think about things like this for once and put up with it!
Mon is no longer the girlfriend she used to be.
Her innocence vanished because of you.
If only you hadn’t even laid a hand on it
Mon wouldn’t become a woman like that anymore.
Don't ever come to my house again.
Promise me you won’t mess with her or anything anymore
I’m sorry.
No matter what you’re told, there’s nothing to be done
Go home.
I’m her brother.
If you had a younger sister too,
you should be able to understand what I did
Go home.
Hey.
If you go straight along that embankment and then turn right, the bus stop is there
The date for the wedding was decided without my input.
Did you say clearly, “I don’t want to”?
I did.
Then?
They had no intention of listening to me.
Did you tell them you were going to disappear?
So long as Sanchan is with me, I’m totally fine
No matter what hardships there are, come with me, okay?
It’s so sudden.
Let’s leave here and talk slowly
I’ll be waiting for you at the next Kobashi bus stop
Please come
Kobashi?
I’ll be waiting for you.
Well then
Sorry about that.
How about the customer?
He has left.
What did he come here to do?
He came here to apologize.
Apparently he's really nice. It’s like he went out of his way to come,
He was very apologetic.—so it’s kind of pitiful, honestly
Mom, I have to go home early today, so—
Huh? Why is that?
I just came to say hello and take
a quick look at your face, that’s all
Are you busy at factory?
you said there’s no overtime right now
Because of the economic downturn…
But if an urgent job comes in,
we’re already short on people, too, you know
Hmm, is that so?
But how about at least taking a day off?
I’m thinking of going back on the next bus.
What?
but I shouldn’t get in trouble, though
If I go now, I’ll make it—then
Next time I come, I'll take my time talking with you.
Hurry up.
Anyway, Let's take it easy around Hakone tonight and talk things over.
Boss. I left a fishing net at your house.
The road ahead is full of trucks, so please drive carefully.
Boss.
What's wrong?
I have never been your boss.
I won’t let someone like that be handled by my hands
I get it.
He has become less able to handle alcohol.
Then, let’s go to Atami
We are going to go by Hakone tomorrow
But....
Don't worry about the money.
I brought my card with me for the money
I can take it out anywhere
This is something like a honeymoon.
Hold on.
(I’ll head home so you don’t waste your money—please don’t spend it unnecessarily.)
Hello.
Old man
May we rent a boat?
This board looks great now that it's been painted.
Oh, sis.
You came from some weird road, didn’t you?
Did we stop by the riverside store?
Was my mom there?
Your dad was asleep.
Really?
Wasn't he minding the shop?
What a lousy dad
But The boats were well-maintained.
Oh, did you see it?
Come on.
Because my mom was complaining
Why is your hairstyle like that?
It's not good.
Say hello.
Hello?
What do you mean 'hello'?
So what are you supposed to say then?
It’s fine if you call me Mom
Go ahead and call
She’ll be surprised
Mom
She's always slow
I'm here.
Hey, come in quickly—you must be getting old
As she grew older, she lost her senses.
Not really.
Hello?
We haven’t seen each other in a while, but
Oh, really?
It’s been a long time
Come on in
I just got my hands dirty a bit, you know
So I thought that for this Bon festival, both of you would come back home
I was getting all fired up since last night, getting everything ready and waiting
San-chan hasn’t been back for quite a while, either
Because, you see, she said she’s going to get some
qualification—an accounting clerk license or something—
and that means she has to
study even on her days off
I thought, well, maybe that’s fine
it’s impressive, really
It’s so hot, isn’t it?
Mom
It looks like a bride came after all like from Marutoyo
I just took a quick look, but...
Hmm, I guess that’s the case
Well, it was already about the time for him to get married
You all come along and try your luck instead of waiting until autumn.
so he really don’t hold back, huh
His wife’s just full of excuses
Tokiko Grandma also came wearing two layers Kimono
Well, underneath the obi belt gets all sweaty, and when she goes into the bath,
it’s like she gave it up for a whole month
Huh, so even boring stories can come through, As usual,
uh, the other day, um...
Oh, that person—Obata-san—he came by
Huh?
Obata-san
When?
I wonder why he came
Huh, so this is his address
It was 3 months ago.
So it was a wig, huh?
He came by and visit us out of the blue
I wonder why.
he showed up and said he
would come up with an apology
He met Dad?
Yes.
What he said?
Dad?, not really—anyway
Did he talk calm?
Yeah, he’s pretty calm—and it’s quite rare for him,
Mr. Obata, Mr.Obata—like, using the polite form, I mean
I was very worried, thinking he would get angry.
but he’s actually fairly gentlemanly
and talked to him gently
I see.
I was sorry.
He didn't need to come here.
Didn’t you meet with my brother?
I didn’t meet with your older brother.
I see.
Whenever he gets involved, there really ends up being trouble.
Fortunately, he was not here.
You know what?
He was really cool, wasn't he?
What?
That person.
You are stupid.
He got you pregnant, you shouldn't be praising him.
I am absolutely fed up.
Mom
Another souvenir?
Sorry about that
My souvenir is there, too.
This?
This is a yukata.
There are 3 of them.
Two of them are for men.
So for dad and Ino?
That is yours.
This?
I thought clothes would be a good choice for you.
This is see-through, isn't it?
You didn't have to buy something so expensive like this.
Is this mine?
This is a really classy pattern of your own, isn’t it?
Look—this isn’t just an ordinary yukata
It says ‘Koubai yukata’ on it
This is for special occasion.
This is lightweight and of very high quality.
Only people from upper-class families own this.
I forgot to pour the tea.
I drink water, so I don't need that.
The water from our well is very delicious.
You see, the water doesn’t come out anymore Lately
They’ve dug a big new well for the air conditioning, and The well has stopped producing water.
I swear it's true—every day they keep building
concrete companies, big dormitories, and apartments.
Your water alone will suffice.
Yeah
Sis.
What was so great about this person named Obata?
I’m sure there are even better people out there in the world.
Sure, there probably are.
The world is a big place
Sure, there were some who were even more handsome—maybe they were starving, or maybe they were generous—
but some were rough and scratchy and all that
You know, he was only that person who was just right
Men are dirty.
If it’s only like me, I’ll do the kind of thing where I make men happy from my side
—something I can do, so that I can laugh at what’s going on inside her—though
Men taught that to me
I don’t know what made me think
this time it’s the real thing, but...
They are all the same
Do you date a guy?
Why?
You want?
I can’t just be thinking about men like that all the time
I’ve got to study too
Marriage isn’t the purpose of my life.
The important thing is living, right?
It sounds pretty serious, doesn’t it?
So if that person named Obata-End comes by right now, What will you do?
I won’t be able to be together with him
I only like him when I’m thinking about him.
He's become lukewarm toward me, too.
You wouldn’t understand, San-chan
Ino!
You work hard.
Hey, is your dad doing well?
Ah, what a shame. You’re still like a monk
well then,
Keep going and earn money.
Ah, you too—quickly, you rush in making money.
Oh my god.
Shall we have a lunch together.
Oi, ugh, it’s so hot.
Leader.
I can’t be motivated without tips—please, I’m counting on you
What? Again?
She really fell asleep
Just leave her alone—she’ll cool off soon
She was so upset
She didn’t get enough sleep or rest
Thank you.
You too—take care, okay?
For what?
Because someone said that at the station saw you
Well, you know
It will be fine.
They’ve taken a wife.
That adopted child turned out to be just fine after all
I thought he’d be a little braver, though
Oh—if he put me up to being brave,
it’ll be the exact same nightmare as what happened before
So were you thrown out?
Are you awake?
I’m going to find a good man for you.
That guy called Okan—or whatever
On the way back, you know, he just bit a manju in the bus
Did you see?
Yeah, he's kind of like a kid
But I hate it.
There’s something cute about him
He look so calm and easygoing.
He can't keep fretting about it for all that time
He's not going to keep taking the blame
Mom
I'm starving.
Hey.
That disgrace of a woman has come back home again.
You’re working even today, huh?
I guess he's just doing this as a temporary helper
pretty interesting, huh?
Even though everyone else has gone back to their home country...
For me, there is no Obon or New Year's.
He spent all his time playing, so he is very busy now.
You probably plans to go on eating for about a week too
I really wish you’d get out of here already—quickly
This is a private home.
During lunch, you can have ankoro and takuan here
I’ll treat you to a meal again
No matter what you do for her, she won't get any better.
Cut it out.
It's been a while, and my sister finally came by, you know?
You'll end up acting like a fool if you get involved with her.
Look—what a great pattern, for a souvenir
Mon bought it for me.
I’ll buy as many rolls as you want
This is for you.
Don’t insult me. I’m not going to come running happily with my
hands out. just because you bought it for me with dirty money
While you don’t have a proper job,
I don’t want you coming around here
Alright, be quiet now—come on, everyone, let’s eat
Hey, sis, you too—let’s eat
Come over here, okay? It’s the break time
We’re about to go to a CM.
Let’s call the fight off—okay?
Tea
Do you want to eat ochazuke?
It’s all over, anyway
What do you mean?
The man who came the other day shouldn't have come here either.
He came here because you are being looked down upon.
You met him?
What happened if I met him?
Where?
I followed him.
He was on his way home.
What did you do?
I knocked him out.
He did not attack me.
My chest felt so light—like a breeze
Hey! Say it again—what did you just say?
What happened to that guy?
I should’ve killed him halfway,
You bastard!
You didn't need to use violence against him.
You have nothing with him
Why do you have to be so rough?
Mon
Sis.
What?
who are you talking to?
You bastard!
This is my body!
Why are you making a big fuss when I did it to him on my own?
Why did you go and half-kill him?!
Stop it! Please!
Why are you hitting and kicking someone
who’s not even lifting a finger?
Shut up!
You're a coward.
Stop!
You bastard!
Please! Bro! Bro! Bro—stop it!
Have you still not woken up?
You bastard!
Stop!
He is an important person to me.
Stop it, Ino.
Stop it
You are nothing but a prostitute.
Bro! Stop it.
Slap me.
Slap me if you want.
You're a country bumpkin—a foolish man living off a woman's money.
You are not my older brother.
You should be mindful of your language and speak in a ladylike manner.
Kill me if you want.
I will.
Bro! Stop it.
Cut it out
Both of you are at fault.
Get out of here already.
You’ve really become quite a woman, huh
Not really, Mom
You don't have to worry so much.
Because you're the first woman I've ever known who could say things like that
Please, I’m begging you
Be serious and get more feminine
because if you carry on like that, you’re no
different from being more than your brother
But I won’t become as awful a woman as my mom thinks I will
But it’s already no good
I don’t need stuff like this anymore!
Anyway, I'm going.
Did you bring incense sticks?
I’ll go offer some to Jizo Statue for Unborn Children too
That is a Jizo statue for babies?
Don’t drink too much
The change for the alcohol is over there—just leave it there
At night, everything looks beautiful, doesn’t it?
It’s romantic, you know
Even if Ino brother is ugly,
It could be.
We'll walk on that bridge?
It's hot, isn't it?
I probably can't come by for a while, though
When will you come again, Sis?
Whenever I ever feel like seeing Mom and others.
Even a brother like that—so awful—I sometimes still feel like seeing his face.
Old man.
Bitches!
Where are you going?
A bus stop.
Don't call us bitches.
Where are you going by bus, Bitches?
A station.
I mean,Where are you going by train?
To Tokyo.
Where in Tokyo?
Our office.
How about you?
Get in the car.
I guess we'll just have to get in the car for his sake.
It's okay to drop us off along the way.
Come back home again.
Mon, Promise me.
Don't go far away from me, okay?
THE END